Ciaran Carson papers, circa 1970-2010
Emory University
Ciaran Carson papers, circa 1970-2010
Carson, Ciaran, 1948-
Manuscript Collection No. 746
29.5 linear ft. (62 boxes) and 27 oversized papers (OP)
Personal and literary papers of Irish poet Ciaran Carson including correspondence, literary notebooks, literary manuscripts, and collected printed material.
Emory University Manuscript, Archives, and Rare Book Library
Source
Purchase, 1993 with subsequent additions.
Restrictions on access
Special restrictions apply: Series 1, Correspondence, letters by Seamus Heaney are closed to researchers.
Biographical Note
Ciaran Gerard Carson (1948-), Irish poet. He was born in Belfast on 9 October 1948. He attended St. Mary's Christian Brothers' School in Belfast before going on to Queen's University, Belfast, where he graduated with honors in July 1971. In the final year of its gathering, 1971-1972, Carson participated in the Belfast group of poets and writers, a gathering of young literary talents organized originally by Philip Hobsbaum at Queens University, Belfast in 1963. After publishing poems in various newspapers and magazines, Carson's first chapbook The Insular Celts appeared in 1973. From 1974-1975 he taught school in Belfast; before joining the Arts Council of Northern Ireland as Traditional Arts Officer in 1976. In 1978, Carson received the Eric Gregory Award for his first book of poems, The New Estate. Three years later he published another chapbook The Lost Explorer (1979). Eight years passed before Carson completed his next volume of poems, The Irish for No (1987), which received the Alice Hunt Bartlett Award. Belfast Confetti (1989), a volume closely related to the 1987 collection, received similar critical success, winning the Irish Times/Aer Lingus prize for poetry.
From 1979 to 1987, Carson continued writing poems and prose pieces including an Appletree Press guide book called Irish Traditional Music, published in 1986. A flutist himself, Carson returned ten years later to a more extensive examination of Irish music with the 1996 publication of the widely heralded Last Night's Fun: About Time, Food and Music. The art of story-telling continued to be a significant aspect of Carson's poetry as seen in First Language, a collection of poems awarded the first T. S. Eliot Prize for the outstanding book of poetry published in Great Britain in 1993. This volume demonstrated Carson's interest in translation including Ovid's Metamorphoses as well as poems written "after" Irish and French originals. 1996 witnessed the publication of Opera Et Cetera, which included a sequence of translations from the Romanian of Stefan Augustin Doinas. Returning to his roots, The Star Factory, Carson's memoir and homage to the Belfast of his childhood followed in 1997.
Leaving the Arts Council in October 1998 to work as a full-time writer, Carson has emerged as one of the major contemporary writers working in English, publishing numerous books of poetry and translations. In 1998, he was appointed a Professor of English at Queen’s University Belfast, where he established the Seamus Heaney Centre for Poetry.
Scope and Content Note
The collection consists of the personal and literary papers of Ciaran Carson from 1970-2010. The papers include correspondence, literary notebooks, literary manuscripts, printed material, subject files, photographs, and personal files. Among the correspondents represented in the papers are the poets Peter Fallon, Tess Gallagher, Seamus Heaney, Medbh McGuckian, John Montague, and Frank Ormsby. Writings include numerous drafts (in manuscript and typescript form) of Carson's published poems and prose, as well as a significant number of unpublished poems. There are also unpublished draft materials and published versions of creative and critical work sent to or collected by Carson. Printed material includes reviews, programs, and clippings related to Carson's writings, performances and readings. The collection also contains early "group sheets" from Philip Hobsbaum's Belfast Group, Arts Council of Northern Ireland records, and an assortment of photographs and other personal items.
Arrangement Note
Organized into nine series: (1) Correspondence, (2) Writings by Carson, (3) Writings by others, (4) Printed material by Carson and others, (5) Belfast Group worksheets, (6) Photographs, (7) Personal materials, (8) Subject files, and (9) Arts Council of Northern Ireland records.
Selected Search Terms
Personal Names
Fallon, Peter, 1951-; Gallagher, Tess.; Heaney, Seamus.; McGuckian, Medbh, 1950-; Montague, John.; Ormsby, Frank, 1947-; Prolux, Annie.; Robinson, Tim, 1935-
Corporate Names
Arts Council of Northern Ireland.
Topical Terms
Arts, Irish.; English literature--Irish authors--20th century.; Irish poetry--20th century.; Poets, Irish--20th century.; Songs, Irish.; Belfast Group.
Geographic Names
Belfast (Northern Ireland); Northern Ireland.
Form/Genre Terms
Manuscripts.; Poems.
Occupation
Poet.
Related Materials in This Repository
Michael Longley papers, Peter Fallon/Gallery Press collection, and Medbh McGuckian papers.
Finding Aid Note
An index to selected correspondents is available for the correspondence from the mid-1970s to 1999.
Description of Series
- Correspondence, 1971-2010, Series 1; Boxes 1-7
  Scope and Content Note
  The correspondence series contains letters Ciaran Carson received from 1971-2010. A substantial part of the correspondence pertains to letters from Carson's various editors: Peter Fallon at Gallery Press, Dillon Johnston at Wake Forest University Press, and Neil Belton at Jonathan Cape and then Granta. There are also significant literary exchanges with scholars and writers from around the world, including Michael Longley, Seamus Heaney (restricted), Medbh McGuckian, Tim Robinson, Annie Proulx, and Tess Gallagher. The Ciaran Carson / Tess Gallagher correspondence is of particular interest because of the very close attention Gallagher pays to Carson's work at both early and late stages of a volume's development. She has served often as a pre-publication editor of most of Carson's major works, and her often extensive annotations are recorded on many typescripts.
  Invitations, contracts, and royalty statements are included in this series and arranged separately from the literary correspondence.
  Arrangement Note
  The correspondence is arranged chronologically. Some correspondence is located with specific writings in Series 2: Writings by Carson.
  Restrictions on access
  Special restrictions apply: Series 1, Correspondence, letters by Seamus Heaney are closed to researchers.
  Finding Aid Note
  An index to selected correspondents is available for the correspondence from the mid-1970s to 1999.
  - 1971-1989 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1990-1992 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1993 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1994 January-March (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1994 April-December (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 1995 January-June (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 1995 July-December (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - 1996 January-March (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - 1996 April-September (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - 1996 October-December (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - 1997 January-May (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - 1997 June-September (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - 1997 October-December (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 1998 January-March (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - 1998 April-June (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - 1998 July-October (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - 1998 November-December (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - 1999 January-June (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - 1999 July-December (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - 2000 January-February (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - 2000 March-April (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - 2000 May-June (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - 2000 July-August (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - 2000 September-October (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - 2000 November-December (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - 2000 indeterminate day and month (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - 2001 January-February (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - 2001 March-April (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - 2001 May-June (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - 2001 July-August (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - 2001 September-October (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - 2001 November-December (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - 2002 January-July (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - 2002 August-October (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - 2002 November-December (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 2003 January-May (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - 2003 June-December (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - 2004 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - 2005 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - 2006 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - 2007 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - 2008 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Undated correspondence [1 of 2] (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Undated correspondence [2 of 2] (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Contracts and royalties statements, 1985-1991 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Contracts and royalties statements, 1992-1994 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Contracts and royalties statements, 1995-1997 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Contracts and royalties statements, 1998-2000 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Contracts and royalties statements, 2001-2008 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous invitations 1978-1993 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous invitations 1994 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous invitations1995 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous invitations 1996-2000 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous invitations 2001-2004 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Restricted correspondence
  - Heaney, Seamus, 1973 (1 item) (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Heaney, Seamus, 1996-1999 (3 items) (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Heaney, Seamus, 2010 (2 items) (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Writings by Carson, circa 1970-2009, Series 2; Boxes 8-28, 48-59; OP1-5
  This series contains writings by Carson including notebooks, manuscript and typescript drafts of poems and prose, translations, scripts, and interviews from 1970-2009.
  Organized into six subseries: (2.1) Notebooks, (2.2) Poetry, (2.3) Translations, (2.4) Prose, (2.5) Scripts for radio and television, and (2.6) Interviews.
  - Notebooks, circa 1970-2007, Subseries 2.1; Boxes 8-11, 48-50
    The notebooks in this series date from the early 1970s to 2007 and include drafts of poems and prose as well as research materials for Carson's published collections during these years. The earliest notebook includes drafts of a variety of poems, some uncollected, from the early 1970's. Early notebooks often contain a diverse array of writings; later ones are dedicated to specific poetry or prose projects. Because there are often several notebooks related to a specific volume, these have been numbered and arranged chronologically in the finding aid.
    Arranged in chronological order.
    - Early notebook, [circa 1970s] (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - The Irish for No notebook, circa 1987 [research notes and drafts of poems] (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Belfast Confetti notebook No. 1, 1987-1989 [research notes on Belfast history and geography] (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Belfast Confetti notebook No. 2, 1986-1992 [drafts of poems and some miscellaneous prose] (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Belfast Confetti notebook No. 3, circa 1988 [research notes and drafts of poems] (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - First Language notebook No. 1, circa 1990 [research notes and drafts of poems and some prose; most is uncollected] (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - First Language notebook No. 2, March 1993 - May 1993 [research notes and drafts of poems] (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - First Language notebook No. 3, July 1993 - August 1993 [research notes and drafts of poems] (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - First Language notebook No. 4, September 1993 - December 1993 [research notes and drafts of poems] (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - First Languag e notebook No. 5, November 1993 - April 1994 [research notes and drafts of poems] (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Opera Et Cetera notebook No. 1, September 1993 - September 1994 [includes some material from First Language plus research notes and drafts of poems for Opera Et Cetera] (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Opera Et Cetera notebook No. 2, September 1994 - December 31, 1995 [research notes and drafts of poems] (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Last Night's Fun notebook No. 1, October - December 1994 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Last Night's Fun notebook No. 2, January - May 1995 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Last Night's Fun notebook No. 3, May - July 1995 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Last Night's Fun and The Star Factory notebook; miscellaneous notes including guest list for Last Night's Fun book launch, emendations to The Star Factory [1996-1997] (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - The Star Factory notebook No. 1, October - December 1995; includes some drafts from "Opera" (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - The Star Factory notebook No. 2, 1995 - 1996 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - The Star Factory notebook No. 3, 1996 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - The Star Factory notebook No. 4, December 1996 - 1997 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - The Star Factory, cut-outs and printed matter stored in notebooks (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - The Alexandrine Plan "French Sonnets" notebook, 1997 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - The Twelfth of Never notebook No. 1, 1997; includes some The Star Factory and miscellaneous notes (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - The Twelfth of Never notebook No. 2, 1997-1998 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Fishing for Amber notebook No. 1, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Fishing for Amber notebook No. 2, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Fishing for Amber notebook No. 3, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Fishing for Amber notebook No. 4, 1998; includes "Bibliography for Fishing for Amber and some notes for Shamrock Tea" (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Shamrock Tea notebook No.1 (1999) (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Shamrock Tea notebook No.2 (1999) (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Shamrock Tea notebook No.3 (1999) (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Inferno notebook, no date (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - Inferno notebook No. 1 (2000) (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Unidentified notebooks, circa 2000s[1 of 2] (Box 48, Folder 2)
    - Unidentified notebooks, circa 2000s [2 of 2] (Box 48, Folder 3)
    - X+Y=K notebook, no date (Box 48, Folder 4)
    - X+Y=K notebook, February 2002 (Box 48, Folder 5)
    - X+Y=K notebook, July 2003 (Box 48, Folder 6)
    - The Pen Friend and X+Y=K notebook, 2002 (Box 48, Folder 7)
    - The Pen Friend notebook No. 1, May - June 2005 (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - The Pen Friend notebook No. 2, May - October 2005 (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - On the Night Watch notebooks, 2004-2005 (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - On the Night Watch notebook, June - August 2008 (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - The Táin notebook, September 2005 (Box 49, Folder 5)
    - The Táin notebook No. 1, November 2005 (Box 49, Folder 6)
    - The Táin notebook No. 2, November - December 2005 (Box 49, Folder 7)
    - The Táin notebook No. 3, December 2005 - February 2006 (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - The Táin notebook No. 4, February 2006 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - The Táin notebook, December 2005 - September 2006 (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - Drafts of unpublished poems, March 2006 (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - For All We Know notebook No. 1, May-June 2007 (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - For All We Know notebook No. 2, August 2007 (Box 50, Folder 6)
  - Poetry, 1971-2009, Subseries 2.2; Boxes 12-18, 50-54; OP 1-2
    This subseries contains manuscript and typescript drafts of poems from 1971-2009. Individual poems are collected by the volume in which they were first published. Folders include manuscript (MS) and/or typescript (TS) versions of the poems. Typescripts and proofs of entire volumes are included at the end of each volume's subsection to roughly demonstrate the chronological development of a published volume. Uncollected poems are filed in a separate subsection. Some poems were originally kept by Carson in folders containing both collected and uncollected manuscripts and typescripts. To assist with the dating of such poems, especially those in the uncollected section, bracketed notes have been added indicating that a particular poem originally was filed by Carson with materials largely pertaining to a specific volume.
    Organized into two sections: (2.2a) Collected poems and (2.2b) Uncollected poetry.
    - Collected poems 1973-2009, Subseries 2.2a; Boxes 12-16, 50-54; OP1
      - The Insular Celts (1973)
      - "The Garden by Night: for Daria," TS [included with the Belfast Group Worksheets 1971-1972 [See also Series 5: Belfast Group Worksheets] (Box 12, Folder 1)
      - "Interior with Weaver," TS [included with the Belfast Group Worksheets 1971-1972 [See also Series 5: Belfast Group Worksheets] [some TS also filed by Carson with materials from The New Estate] (Box 12, Folder 2)
      - "The Island Revisted," TS [See Series 5: Belfast Group Worksheets] (Box -, Folder -)
      - "Letter from Alaska," TS [See Series 5: Belfast Group Worksheets] (Box -, Folder -)
      - "O'Carolan's Complaint," TS [fragment] [originally filed by Carson with materials from The New Estate] (Box 12, Folder 3)
      - "St. Ciaran's Island," TS [originally filed by Carson with materials from The New Estate] (Box 12, Folder 4)
      - "Wheel," MS and TS [originally filed by Carson with materials from The New Estate] [See also Series 5: Belfast Group Worksheets] (Box 12, Folder 5)
      - The New Estate (1976)
      - "Belleek," TS [See also Subseries 2.2: The New Estate, "To a married Sister"] (Box 12, Folder 6)
      - "The Bomb Disposal," TS (Box 12, Folder 7)
      - "Collecting Stamps," MS (Box 12, Folder 8)
      - "Fishes in a Chinese Restaurant," TS (Box 12, Folder 9)
      - "The Half-Moon Lake," TS (Box 12, Folder 10)
      - "The Holiday," TS (Box 12, Folder 11)
      - "Moving In," TS (Box 12, Folder 12)
      - "The New Estate," MS and TS (Box 12, Folder 13)
      - "Sickness," MS (Box 12, Folder 14)
      - "Soot," TS [variant titles: "Visiting the Sick," "Falling Asleep Thinking of Gowns"] (Box 12, Folder 15)
      - "To Margaret," MS and TS [See also Subseries 2.2: Uncollected Poems, "Snow"] (Box 12, Folder 16)
      - "To a Married Sister," TS [variant title: "The Married Sister"] (Box 12, Folder 17)
      - "Visiting the Dead," TS (Box 12, Folder 18)
      - The Lost Explorer (1978)
      - "Africa," TS (Box 12, Folder 19)
      - "East of Cairo," MS and TS (Box 12, Folder 20)
      - "The Great Fitzpatrick," MS and TS (Box 12, Folder 21)
      - "Great-Grandmother," TS [variant title: "An Early Photograph"] [See also Subseries 2.2: Uncollected Poems, "First Times"] (Box 12, Folder 22)
      - "The Incredible Shrinking Man," TS (Box 12, Folder 23)
      - "The Patchwork Quilt," TS (Box 12, Folder 24)
      - "The Rosary Rally," MS [variant title: "The Great Rosary Rally"] (Box 12, Folder 25)
      - "Smithfield," MS and TS [variant title: "Brothers"] [original MS filed by Carson with materials from The New Estate] (Box 12, Folder 26)
      - "Twine," TS (Box 12, Folder 27)
      - "Visitors," MS and TS (Box 12, Folder 28)
      - The Irish for No (1987)
      - "Army," TS [variant title: "Then Three Were None "] (Box 12, Folder 29)
      - "Asylum," TS (Box 12, Folder 30)
      - "August 1969," TS (Box 12, Folder 31)
      - "Belfast Confetti," TS [See also Subseries 2.2: Belfast Confetti, "Ambition"] (Box 12, Folder 32)
      - "Box," TS (Box 12, Folder 33)
      - "Calvin Klein's Obsession," TS (Box 12, Folder 34)
      - "Cocktails," TS (Box 12, Folder 35)
      - "Dresden," TS (Box 12, Folder 36)
      - "Exile's Club," TS (Box 12, Folder 37)
      - "Judgement," TS (Box 12, Folder 38)
      - "Linear B," TS (Box 12, Folder 39)
      - "Night Patrol," TS (Box 12, Folder 40)
      - "Patchwork," TS (Box 12, Folder 41)
      - "Slate Street School," TS (Box 12, Folder 42)
      - "Smithfield Market," TS (Box 12, Folder 43)
      - "Snowball," TS (Box 12, Folder 44)
      - "33333," TS (Box 12, Folder 45)
      - "Travellers," MS and TS (Box 12, Folder 46)
      - "Two Winos," TS (Box 12, Folder 47)
      - "Whatever Sleep It Is," TS (Box 12, Folder 48)
      - The Irish for No, part two early typescript "drafts" with Tess Gallagher's annotations (Box 12, Folder 49)
      - The Irish for No, part one, typescript [photocopy] (Box 12, Folder 50)
      - The Irish for No, part two typescript [photocopy] (Box 12, Folder 51)
      - The Irish for No, part three typescript [photocopy] (Box 12, Folder 52)
      - The Irish for No, section title pages typescript (Box 12, Folder 53)
      - The New Estate and Other Poems (1988)
      - "The Alhambra," MS [originally filed by Carson with materials from The New Estate] (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - "Dunne," MS and TS (Box 13, Folder 2)
      - "Epitaph," TS [variant title: "Epitaphs;" includes numbered sections variously entitled: "The Lost Girl" and "Epitaph"] [originally filed by Carson with materials from The New Estate] [See also Subseries 2.2: The New Estate, "Collecting Stamps"] (Box 13, Folder 3)
      - "Grandfather," TS [originally filed by Carson with materials from The Lost Explorer] (Box 13, Folder 4)
      - "Post," TS [variant title: "Waste"] (Box 13, Folder 5)
      - "Stitch," TS (Box 13, Folder 6)
      - Belfast Confetti (1989)
      - "All the Better to See You With," MS and TS [variant title: "Dream Wedding"] (Box 13, Folder 7)
      - "Ambition," TS (Box 13, Folder 8)
      - "Barfly," TS (Box 13, Folder 9)
      - "Bed-Time Story," MS and TS (Box 13, Folder 10)
      - "Farset," MS (Box 13, Folder 11)
      - "Gate," MS and TS [variant title: "33 University Road / Street"] [See also Subseries 2.2: Belfast Confetti, "All the Better to See You With" and "Last Orders"] (Box 13, Folder 12)
      - "Hairline Crack," TS (Box 13, Folder 13)
      - "Hamlet," MS and TS [variant titles: "Hamlet's Father's Helmet," and "The Meaning of the Falls Road"] [See also Subseries 2.2: The Irish for No, "A Ghost Story"] (Box 13, Folder 14)
      - "The Heart," [See Subseries 2.2: Belfast Confetti, "The Mouth" and Belfast Confetti, TS with corrections] (Box -, Folder -)
      - "Jawbox," TS [variant title: "Belfast Sink"] (Box 13, Folder 15)
      - "John Ruskin in Belfast," TS (Box 13, Folder 16)
      - "Jump Leads," MS (Box 13, Folder 17)
      - "The Knee,' TS (Box 13, Folder 18)
      - "Last Orders," TS [variant title: "The Hole in the Wall"] [Subseries 2.2: also Belfast Confetti, "Gate"] (Box 13, Folder 19)
      - "Loaf," MS and TS [variant titles: "Sliced Pan Seventeen", "Sliced Pan"] (Box 13, Folder 20)
      - "The Mouth," TS (Box 13, Folder 21)
      - "Narrative in Black and White," TS [variant title: "Narrative in Black and Red"] (Box 13, Folder 22)
      - "Night Out," TS [See also Subseries 2.2: Uncollected Poems, "Snowstorm"] (Box 13, Folder 23)
      - "Punctuation," MS and TS [variant title: "Crossfire"] (Box 13, Folder 24)
      - "Queen's Gambit,' MS and TS [variant title: "Big Ears"] (Box 13, Folder 25)
      - "Schoolboys and Idlers of Pompeii," [research material] [See also Subseries 2.2: Uncollected Poems, "Alphabet City"] (Box 13, Folder 26)
      - "Snow," TS (Box 13, Folder 27)
      - "Yes," TS (Box 13, Folder 28)
      - Belfast Confetti, jacket blurb / volume introduction, MS (Box 13, Folder 29)
      - Belfast Confetti, research materials and other notes [from notebook No. 3] (Box 13, Folder 30)
      - Belfast Confetti, table of contents, MS and TS (Box 13, Folder 31)
      - Belfast Confetti, typescript with corrections [includes uncollected poems] (Box 13, Folder 32)
      - Belfast Confetti, typescript with corrections (Box 13, Folder 33)
      - First Language (1994)
      - "The Albatross," TS (Box 14, Folder 1)
      - "All Souls," TS (Box 14, Folder 2)
      - "Apparat," MS and TS (Box 14, Folder 3)
      - "Ark of the Covenant," MS (Box 14, Folder 4)
      - "Bagpipe Music," TS [for Guinn Batten] (Box 14, Folder 5)
      - "The Ballad of HMS Belfast," MS and TS [variant title: "The Voyages of H.M.S. Belfast"] (Box 14, Folder 6)
      - "The Brain of Edward Carson," TS (Box 14, Folder 7)
      - "Contract," MS and TS [variant title: "Apparat"] (Box 14, Folder 8)
      - "Correspondances," MS and TS (Box 14, Folder 9)
      - "A Date Called Eat Me," MS (Box 14, Folder 10)
      - "Drunk Boat," MS and TS (Box 14, Folder 11)
      - "58," MS and TS [variant title: "Squeegee"] (Box 14, Folder 12)